<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Dialogue between a director of the new East-India Company and one of the committee for preparing by-laws for the said company in which those for a rotation of directors and the preventing of bribes are particularly debated.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1699</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 62 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A35860</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D1293</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R343</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11776858</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11776858</idno>
            <idno type="VID">48951</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A35860)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 48951)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 25:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Dialogue between a director of the new East-India Company and one of the committee for preparing by-laws for the said company in which those for a rotation of directors and the preventing of bribes are particularly debated.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>29 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Andrew Bell ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Columbia University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>East India Company.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:48951:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:48951:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A DIALOGUE Between a DIRECTOR Of the New <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company, And one of the COMMITTEE for preparing By-Laws for the ſaid Company. In which Thoſe for a ROTATION of <hi>Directors,</hi> and the preventing of <hi>BRIBES</hi> are particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larly debated.</p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Prov. 1.17.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>Surely in vain the Net is ſpread in the ſight of any Bird.</p>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Andrew Bell</hi> at the Croſs-keys and Bible in <hi>Cornhil.</hi> M.DC.XC.IX.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="dialogue">
            <pb facs="tcp:48951:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:48951:2"/>
            <head>A DIALOGUE BETWEEN A Director of the New <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company, and one of the Committee for preparing <hi>By-Laws</hi> for the ſaid Company, concerning thoſe particular things propoſed for <hi>By-Laws</hi> which are diſliked by the Directors.</head>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Direct.</speaker>
               <p>I Am glad to find you here alone, that if your Buſineſs will permit, we may have a little diſcourſe about ſome By-Laws that you and others of the Committee ſeem earneſt for, which are not agreeable to our Directors; and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps when you have heard the Reaſons I have to offer againſt them, you will be of another mind. There are ſeveral that you propoſe, which we diſlike; but that which more eſpecially diſpleaſeth us is a ROTATION. The Word is not common, and the Method (if I apprehend it right) is not practiſed in any Companies amongſt us; therefore pray explain to me what you mean by it: for the Directors are alarm'd at it, and reſolve with all their Power and Intereſt to oppoſe it; and in order to that end, they are prepoſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing their Friends and Acquaintance with Prejudices againſt it.</p>
            </sp>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:48951:3"/>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Committ.</speaker>
               <p>The Rotation deſired is in ſhort this: That no Man ſhall continue a Director above three years ſucceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſively, nor be excluded from being a Director above one year in four; ſo that every year there ſhall be a Change of eight, that the whole twenty four may fall off, or be changed in the ſpace of three years; and yet the eight that go off one year may come in the next, and continue three years more ſucceſſively, if choſen.</p>
               <p>Thus thoſe Directors that have the general eſteem of the Members, may not be out above one year in ſeven: which will be only a little retreat from the Hurry of Buſineſs, that every wiſe man would chuſe, tho he were not obliged to it.</p>
               <p>And for my part, I cannot ſee that this Method will be at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended with any ill Conſequences to the Company's Affairs, that ſhould cauſe in the Directors ſuch a diſpleaſure againſt it, as you ſay it doth; but on the contrary it will be a great means to prevent that Corruption amongſt them, that one continued Set of Directors would naturally pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce.</p>
               <p>The Wiſdom of this Nation found many Inconveniencies in long Parliaments; and therefore enacted that there ſhould be a new one every three years; which is as much of the manner of a Rotation as the nature of that thing will admit: And if there be a neceſſity for the frequent Change of Parliaments, there ſeems a much greater neceſſity for a frequent Change of the Directors of a Company, where the Temptations are great, and Opportunities of getting Money by indirect ways do offer themſelves continually; as by Preſents, Gifts, and Bribes, Private Trade, and many other ways that Committee-men of other Companies have found out, and may in time be diſcovered by the dexterous Managers of this New Company.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>I underſtand the manner of the Rotation you deſire, which ſeems principally intended to prevent Corruption a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt the Directors; but I do not underſtand that you
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:48951:3"/>have Power to make ſuch a By-Law if it was convenient; becauſe the words of your Charter ſay that the twenty four that have the majority of Votes ſhall be your Direc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, and this By-Law would exclude eight of the Direc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors every Year, altho they ſhould have the majority of Votes. So that this is repugnant to your Charter; and notwithſtanding any By-Law you can make to the contrary, thoſe that ſhall have the moſt Votes may inſiſt upon their Right to the Directorſhip by virtue of your Charter: And if they do ſo, will have Remedy in <hi>Weſtminſter Hall.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>If the Company have no Power to make ſuch a By-Law, it would be in vain to attempt it; for if it was made, it would be null and void in it ſelf: but ſome Gentlemen of the long Robe, and thoſe of the firſt Rank, ſay, ſuch a By-Law is not repugnant to our Charter, and when con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm'd by the General Court will be valid. Therefore I am of Opinion few Men would think it adviſeable to inſiſt upon their Right of Election in oppoſition to this By-Law; If any ſhould be ſo ſtubborn to diſpute it, the General Court hath Power to turn them out, and doubtleſs will aſſert their Power in ſuch a Caſe. But, Sir, to put this matter paſt all doubt, the By-Law may run thus: That at the next Annual Election none ſhall put in their Liſts the Names of more than ſixteen of the old Directors; and at the next following Annual Election, they ſhall not put in their Liſts more than eight of the Names of thoſe that have ſerved two Years. And at the third Annual Election, they ſhall not put in their Liſts any Names of thoſe eight that have ſerved three Years. And if any Liſts be found contrary to this By-Law, the Scrutineers ſhall have Power and be obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to reject them; and of this, publick Notice may be given in the Printed Liſts before every Annual Elec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
               <p>By this Method the words of the Charter will not be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradicted, but thoſe twenty four that have the moſt Votes will be the Directors: And Certainly a General Court
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:48951:4"/>hath Power to make a By-Law to change as many Direc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors yearly as they pleaſe, keeping ſtill to the Method above, that thoſe that have the moſt Votes ſhall be the Directors.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>But granting you have a power to make ſuch a By-Law, the queſtion will be whether it be expedient; and I have two very good Reaſons to offer againſt the expediency of it. For firſt, it takes away that liberty of Choice that the Charter gives you; for now you have liberty to chuſe whom you pleaſe, but this By-Law reſtrains you, and ſays you ſhall every Year change eight altho you are unwilling to change any: and methinks while the general Court hath a Power to turn out all, or as many of the Directors as they pleaſe, and when they pleaſe, this is a needleſs Law, and ſeems to take away, or leſſen the Power now veſted in the General Court; for what need we oblige our ſelves to change eight every Year, when we have Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er if we think it for our Advantage, not only to change eight, but all the four and twenty? And</p>
               <p>Secondly, This By-Law is not expedient, becauſe it obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geth us to lay aſide every Director one Year in four; which may be of very ill conſequence to the Company's Affairs, becauſe in all Companies there are uſually ſome particular Men that by their Parts, Application and Experience at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain to great Dexterity and Skill in the Buſineſs under their management above the reſt; and ſuch Men the Company cannot with ſafety part withal: they become ſo uſeful and neceſſary, that if it were poſſible they ſhould ſit at the Helm all their Lives, to direct the Affairs of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</p>
               <p>I think theſe Arguments againſt the expediency of this By-Law carry ſo much weight, that to me they ſeem unan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwerable; but if you can give me better Reaſons for the expediency of it than I have given you againſt it, I ſhall be willing to hear them: for it is againſt Fleſh and Blood to part with three ſuch dear things, as are Power, Honour, and Profit.</p>
            </sp>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:48951:4"/>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>Your Arguments againſt the expediency of a Rota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion ſeem very plauſible and ſtrong; they carry with them a fair ſhow and appearance, and may doubtleſs obtain with many who do not give themſelves leiſure to conſider and examine them. Yet were it not for thoſe dear things you laſt mentioned, I ſhould hope to convince you and all the Directors, as I doubt not to do every Man that is not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judiced.</p>
               <p>I grant that the Charter doth veſt the General Courts with a Power to do all thoſe things you mention, to place and diſplace Directors at their pleaſure: but the pinch is here; How ſhall they come to uſe or exert that Power? For the Queſtion is not here, what we may or have liberty by our Charter to do; but what we can do, or is in our power to do, the nature and circumſtances of things being duly conſidered. For there muſt be a majority in a Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Court to do it: the General Court will not turn out any Director unleſs they are ſatisfied of his unfitneſs for their Service; and pray which way can they be ſatisfied, but only by ſufficient Proof in an open Court? And I would gladly ſee that Perſon that will undertake to accuſe any Director in a General Court, and prove his Crimes or Unfitneſs for their Service to the ſatisfaction of a major part.</p>
               <p>As the matter ſtands now with us, notwithſtanding all this noiſe of Power to turn out and put in at pleaſure, I ſay a General Court cannot turn out a Man unleſs they can lay their fingers on a Director, and ſay this Man is not fit for our Service, for ſuch and ſuch Reaſons; which muſt alſo be proved (as I obſerved before) to the ſatisfaction of the majority of the Members then preſent: which is ſo difficult a matter, that as I have not, ſo I never expect to ſee an Inſtance of it. What I have now ſaid is only with reſpect to the turning out of any particular Member or Members between the times of annual Elections: for what can be done by a General Court at the annual Elections as to the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:48951:5"/>changing of Directors, ſhall be ſpoke to by and by. But be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I come to that Point, I ſhall obſerve to you, that the General Court hath in effect no Power to fill the Place of any Director that happens to die within the Year, or doth for any Reaſon whatever voluntarily quit their Service: For tho every Member having five hundred pound Stock hath liberty to vote for whom he pleaſeth, yet it hath al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways been obſerved in the Bank of <hi>England</hi> that between the Annual Elections, when only one, two or three Direc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors were to be choſen, very few Members did concern themſelves in thoſe Elections; ſo that the Choice hath been uſually carried by ſeventy or eighty odd Votes, and the common Method hath been, that the Directors have agreed together upon a Perſon or Perſons that they liked to fill up the Vacancy, and accordingly made their own Liſts, and diſtributed the ſame amongſt their Friends and Acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance; and ſo they never failed, nor can ever fail, of ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the very Perſon or Perſons they deſire. For ſuppoſe every Director can but engage three Perſons Votes beſides his own, they will certainly carry any ſuch ſingle Election: and he muſt be a Man of a very ſmall Intereſt and Repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, or recommend ſome infamous Perſon indeed, that cannot procure three or four Votes beſides his own. And as this hath been, and is ever like to be, the practice in the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> ſo it is natural to believe, it will ever be the Practice in this Company: and I muſt confeſs I know no Remedy againſt it.</p>
               <p>Thus you ſee the General Courts have the Name, and the Directors the Power, to place and diſplace ſingle Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors. Let us now conſider what General Courts can do in changing Directors at the Annnal Elections. And we may make ſome gueſs at it by what hath been done in the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> which is a Conſtitution that comes the neareſt to that of this Company of any we have amongſt us, and indeed as to Elections is the very ſame. And there we find, till the Parliament did remedy that Evil, there could
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:48951:5"/>be no Change of Directors; but till that time from their firſt Eſtabliſhment, the very ſame Men. were continued without the alteration of one ſingle Perſon, except thoſe that voluntarily reſign'd, and <hi>Patterſon</hi> for ſome notorious Crimes, and ſo had continued till this very day, and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps as long as the Bank will continue, except where Death interven'd, or that they had fallen out among them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves. There were Attempts and Endeavours uſed by the Members to make ſome alterations at every new Choice, but all in vain; the Directors Liſts always prevailed, not that the firſt twenty four were the beſt and fitteſt Men in all the Company, or had an univerſal Reputation of being ſuch, but thoſe old ones did generally combine and confe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derate together, and by that means made a greater Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt for one another, than could be made for any other Perſons (not of their Number) by a General Court, where the Members are not known to one another, have divided Intereſts, are unacquainted with Men, cannot poſſibly have any combinations together, and in general take ſuch Liſts as are offer'd them, which for the moſt part are ſuch as the Directors and their Friends diſperſe amongſt the Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, who have heard the Names of thoſe that are Direc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors (for by Name they are known to all the Company) and tho perhaps they neither know their Perſons nor Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications, yet they think they may as well be govern'd by thoſe they have heard of, as thoſe they have not; and ſo they take the Liſts <hi>de bene eſſe,</hi> and many times put them into the Glaſs without ſcruple or reading. Some may be ſo curious as to read the Names, and ask Queſtions about them; but they are ſure to have a favourable Character given by thoſe that recommend them. Some indeed will alter a Name or two, and put in their room others they know or think to be honeſt Men, their Neighbours or Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance. Another alters another Name or Names for ſome other Perſons he eſteems; yet this can never bring in their Friends, nor exclude the others, but ſtill the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:48951:6"/>Liſt prevails; for perhaps I put in the Name of one that may not be in two Liſts beſides, another doth the ſame, a third likewiſe, and ſo on. Thus I leave out one Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, another keeps him in and leaves out another, a third and fourth do ſo likewiſe; but all this doth not help their Friends, nor hurt thoſe they would exclude. For unleſs the putting in and leaving out of Names be general, it can ſignifie nothing. This is ſo plain and experienced a Truth, that you Directors all know it, and every Man that will but conſider a little will eaſily diſcern it. Therefore tho you ſay a Rotation will take away from General Courts that Liberty of Choice the Charter gives them, and what they now enjoy, I do affirm, and it is evident by conſidering what I have already ſaid, that as the matter now ſtands, the General Court hath in effect no liberty of Choice at all, but the whole Power of Elections is lodged with the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors; and without a Rotation they will always keep themſelves in, or what Directors they pleaſe, in ſpite of General Courts. Nothing can be an equal Ballance to the Direſtors Lifſt, except you can ſuppoſe twenty four other Members all of as great Intereſt, and as univerſally known to the Members of the Company as the Directors are; and that thoſe twenty four join together to make and diſperſe one Liſt: which is not to be imagined for ſundry Reaſons, that are ſo obvious that I ſhall not ſpend time to mention them.</p>
               <p>But, Sir, to evince the Truth of what I have ſaid concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the Power the Directors have to govern and influ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence Elections, let us look back and conſider what they have done already in their Infancy; by which we may con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jecture what they will do, or at leaſt may do hereafter. And firſt, before they were Directors, or conſequently were ſo well known as they are now, or will be ſome time hence, they met together, agreed upon one Liſt of twenty four, and carried every Man in it but three to be Directors. The next Choice was a Committee of twenty four for
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:48951:6"/>preparing By-Laws, about which the Directors alſo met, agreed upon a Liſt, and had them all choſen but two. And as the Elections have hitherto been wholly governed by the Wills and Power of the Directors, ſo they will always continue to be, except we eſtabliſh a Rotation by a By-Law to prevent it: which I think is the only means we can uſe to hinder and avoid Combinations and Confederacies, and many other Inconveniencies and Miſchiefs that will follow them; of which more anon.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>If you are of Opinion the Directors can bring in and keep out whom they pleaſe, you act againſt your own Intereſt to ſhew ſo much zeal for a By-Law ſo diſpleaſing to them all: for this firmneſs of yours in this and ſome other matters doth exaſperate them againſt you to the high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt degree, that there is no expectation they will ever admit you into their Number, of which before there was a fair proſpect; and then you might probably have continued in that Station all your Life, which would have been much more for your advantage than you can reap by ſtriving for this By-Law, which the Directors are reſolved ſhall never paſs. So you are like to loſe both the By-Law, and all hopes of ever being a Director.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>I readily grant I have acted againſt my Intereſt, if a Directorſhip and Profit may be reckon'd ſo: but thoſe things were not my Aim; if they had, I knew a nearer way to have obtain'd them. I am entruſted by the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Court to aſſiſt in preparing ſuch By-Laws as my un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biaſs'd Reaſon, Judgment, and Conſcience tell me are for the general good of the Company; and not by any baſe compliance to betray my Truſt, tho to my own advantage. If I am in the wrong, it proceeds from an Error of my Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, not of my Will; and all the World ſhall not make me ſpeak or vote contrary to my Reaſon, and what I appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hend for the Benefit and Safety of the Company; nor ſneak away or abſent my ſelf purpoſely from the Committee for fear of incurring ſome Gentlemens diſpleaſure. For he
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:48951:7"/>that hath Meaſures to keep, Intereſts to ſerve, and ſtands in fear of diſpleaſing others, can hardly be an honeſt Man, and is certainly unfit for any publick Truſt. Such a Man dares not act according to the Dictates of his own Reaſon and Conſcience, but proſtitutes both to the Will of his Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trons. And methinks if your Directors that are ſo violent and angry would ſeriouſly conſider it, they would think that we have as much Reaſon to be angry with them for dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering in Opinion from us, as they have to be angry with us for differing in Opinion from them, except they can pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to Infallibility or Revelation.</p>
               <p>I would ask your angry Men this plain ſhort Queſtion, Whether upon any Debate they give their Opinions and Votes according to their Judgment or not? I muſt take it for granted they will anſwer, they do; and if ſo, why do they blame us for acting as they do themſelves?</p>
               <p>You have led me into a long Digreſſion: but I will now proceed to conſider the ſecond Argument againſt the expediency of a Rotation, which centers in this, That uſual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſome Men in all Companies attain to ſuch a Degree of skill in managing their Affairs, that the Company cannot well be without them.</p>
               <p>This Argument will ſerve as well for the Continuation of Magiſtrates, Miniſters and Secretaries of State for Life: and yet we find wiſe People, and jealous of their Liberties, make frequent Changes of them. The little State of <hi>Luc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ca</hi> in <hi>Italy</hi> by changing their Magiſtrates every two Months, and the Reſtraint they are kept under while they bear Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, have preſerved their Liberty while moſt of their neighbouring States have loſt theirs. And the Secretaries of State one would think more neceſſary to be continued, on account of their Skill, Experience and Knowledg of pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Affairs, than any Director in an <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company. Yet we have ſeen many Changes made of them, even here at home, without any harm or prejudice to the State.</p>
               <p>But further, this Argument of yours is againſt any
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:48951:7"/>Change of Directors at all; for it muſt be ſuppoſed that thoſe that fall off have more knowledg of the Affairs of the Company than new ones that have not been Directors be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore. And ſo by a parity of Reaſon we ſhould always continue the ſame Men, becauſe new ones have leſs Skill and Experience than the old ones. This indeed might be a good Method to have always a Set of Directors that are acquainted with the Company's Buſineſs; but it is to be fea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red they would alſo be acquainted with ways of making Advantages to themſelves, diſtinct and ſeparate from that of the Company: and then how knowing ſoever they might be in the Company's Buſineſs, that would be ſure to be made ſubſervient to their own Intereſt, and all their thoughts turn'd to their private gain.</p>
               <p>In the Old Company we have ſeen this verified; for there ſome Perſons have been Committee Men many Years toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and doubtleſs did, or at leaſt had opportunities e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough of attaining to a perfect Knowledg of that Company's Affairs; and yet the ſingle Advantage of that Company was neglected, while they employed their Thoughts, Time and Study how to raiſe Eſtates to themſelves by private Trade, Contracts, Preſents and Gifts, to hold parts of Ships, get<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting them into the Company's Service, furniſhing Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manders with Neceſſaries for their Voyages, or by Loans on Bottomaree, at great Premiums, and many other ways, that thoſe skilful Men by being acquainted with the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany's Affairs did diſcover. And can we ſuppoſe our Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors will be ignorant of thoſe private ways, or will be more kind and honeſt to us then they were to the Old Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, if we continue them perpetual Directors, as they will be without a Rotation? for our Directors are Fleſh and Blood as well as thoſe Committee Men; nor have they in their private Capacities a fairer Reputation than thoſe Men had, and I dare ſay, give them the ſame opportunities, they will do the ſame things: for tho I do not think all Men are a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like, yet I believe the moſt are ſo.</p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:48951:8"/>
               <p>If there be any particular Men amongſt them more uſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful and knowing than the reſt, doubtleſs we ſhall hear with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out doors who they are, and always keep them in the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement till the fourth Year: but I would have them kept in for their Merits and deſerved Reputation, and not by the Art and Force of Cabals, Combinations and Confederacies, which oftentimes have kept in the worſt as well as the beſt in other Societies. For none ever thought that all thoſe that are Directors in the Bank of <hi>England</hi> were the wiſeſt Men in that Company, or were choſen ſo many Years ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſively for their Parts, Merits, or the greatneſs of their Caſh; but they chanced to fall into the Confederacies, and their Names being known by reaſon of the publick Places they had ſerved in, or the Gold Chains they had worn, were the chief Cauſe of their being choſen by ſo great a majority of Votes.</p>
               <p>Now it is probable by a Rotation there would not be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove eight changed every Year, ſo ſixteen of the old ones would remain till next Election; and by that time eight of the ſixteen go off, the firſt eight new ones will have got ſome knowledg; and if they be Men of reaſonable Abilities and Application, they may be very perfect before the oldeſt eight fall off: ſo that we cannot juſtly fear ever wanting ſome Men of Parts and Skill to direct the Company's Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs.</p>
               <p>But I do not ſee what great occaſion we have for ſuch ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traordinary Men of Skill and Cunning, except we were to make War with the Great <hi>Mogul,</hi> or cheat the <hi>Indians.</hi> I hope we deſign nothing but a fair honeſt Trade; and for the management of that it is always obſerved, Men of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fined Wit and Parts are not ſo apt and proper as thoſe of a middle Capacity. There is no ſuch Witchcraft in the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Trade, but any Merchant or other well vers'd in foreign Trade and Buſineſs may be a fit Director: if it be not ſo, I doubt our New Company will be but ill di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected by ſome of the preſent Managers.</p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:48951:8"/>
               <p>We have had a late Inſtance in the Management of the Affairs of the <hi>Antelope</hi> an Interloper, how ſome of thoſe Directors of the New Company who are thought to be ſuch uſeful and extraordinary Men for diſpatch of Buſineſs that they ought to be continued in that Station all their Lives, have skill and dexterity enough to perplex Accompts, and under the colour of various pretences to defer making of Dividends; and when they have been appointed, can ſtill find out freſh excuſes to keep the Proprietors out of their Mony: whereas a Set of Men leſs famous for their Conduct, have been much more expeditious in dividing the Mony of the <hi>Scarborough</hi> and <hi>Rebecca.</hi> And I hope no body can with Reaſon expect ſuch Men will be more punctual and leſs ſelf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ended in a more publick Concern.</p>
               <p>But pray let us examine into the particulars of this Trade, that we may the better diſcover the Difficulties of it. For if People will take things in groſs, they may be eaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly impos'd upon by the ſpecious Arguments of there being a perfect neceſſity to have ſome extraordinary Men always continued at the Helm of our Affairs, and the danger of changing them. And I think upon viewing the particulars, we ſhall find nothing of ſuch an extraordinary nature, but that Men of ordinary Capacities, that have been a Year or two acquainted with them may be able to manage.</p>
               <p>For here at home their Buſineſs is to buy Goods and Pie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Eight, and freight Ships, look after the Accompts, and correſpond with People abroad; and for the manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of theſe there are four diſtinct Committees. They have farther, to chuſe Factors and ſettle Factories and Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laries, draw up Inſtructions for the Ambaſſador, provide Preſents proper to be ſent with him, give directions for ſuch ſortments of <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Goods as may be fit for our Market, and direct and manage the Sales of them at home.</p>
               <p>Under theſe Heads all the Company's Buſineſs may be comprehended, and ſome of them are already done, and
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:48951:9"/>may not need repeating theſe ſeveral Years; as the Form of a Charter-Party, Choice of Factors, Setling of Facto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries and Salaries, Inſtructions to the Ambaſſador, and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents to go with him. Some changes and alterations in theſe things may be requiſite hereafter, but there can be no great difficulty in them. And certainly if twenty four Men, moſt of whom have no knowledg of the <hi>India</hi> Trade at all, and the skilfulleſt have been only concerned in three or four In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terlopers, are able to lay a good Foundation and Scheme for ſo great a Trade, it cannot be thought difficult for ſuch as ſhall be hereafter choſen, with the aſſiſtance of thoſe that have been in the management two Years together, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving their Scheme, Letters, and Orders all before them, to direct and carry it on to the Honour of the Nation and Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage of the Company. However we need not fear half thoſe inconveniencies and Diſadvantages by thoſe Managers that we may juſtly apprehend from a few arbitrary Men, when the Directorſhips are entailed upon them, as they will be without a Rotation.</p>
               <p>When ſuch men are once fixt in their Stations by a re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection of this By-law, you will ſoon have them turn their thoughts upon private Trade, and find means to elude the Act of Parliament, Charter, and all our By-Laws. They will tell you they were bred Merchants, and men of buſineſs, and it is not worth their while to ſpend their time in the Company's Service for a bare Salary of 150 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> (for ſo much it is ſaid they expect at leaſt) and it is unreaſonable that Gentlemen and others ſhould follow their Pleaſures and Imployments, and yet reap equal Advantages in Trade with them that are bred to it, and ſpend their time in it. Thus they will form to themſelves Reaſons why little Perquiſites beſides their Salaries ſhould be indulged them; and when they allow themſelves to go beyond their Salaries, they will have no bounds, nor can we tell where they will ſtop. Of this we have an example in the Old Company, where their Committee-men, under pretence of a lean and ſcanty Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:48951:9"/>for their trouble, have thought it lawful for them to make all the Advantages they could, ſeparate from that of the Joint Stock: and ſo while the other Members ſtar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, the Managers grew fat and full; not that I believe a large Salary will ſecure us from ſome Directors indirect Practices: Nature will have its Courſe; and you may as well expect to ſecure your Lambs and Poultry from a ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venous Fox, by giving him a plentiful Allowance, as your Stock by a large Salary to an unconſcionable Director; for give the Fox as much as you will, if you do not keep him chained, he will be at his Game; it is his nature and can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be cured.</p>
               <p>A few perpetual Directors ſhall have all our Servants in <hi>India</hi> to worſhip them; and to make their Worſhip accept<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, no Offerings or Oblations muſt be ſpared: At home all Applications and Addreſſes ſhall be made to them; and as the Cuſtom is amongſt us, none muſt approach empty handed. Theſe leading men muſt furniſh the Captains, ſome with Oxen, others with Powder, others with Guns and Shot, others with Beer, Cordage, Iron-work, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and that at their own Rates: but what is paid extraordinary by the Captains, the Company loſes at laſt. Theſe and innume<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable other miſchiefs a thorow Rotation would in a great meaſure prevent; and if I had all my Eſtate in this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, I would rather chuſe and think it ſafer to have a tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row Rotation in three Years without any By-Laws, than the beſt By-Laws without any Change of Directors. But it is near two a Clock by my Watch, we ſhall loſe our <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change</hi> unleſs we leave off for this time: when we meet a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, I have ſomewhat further to offer on this Subject.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>I ſhall gladly hear all you have to ſay. If I miſtake not, you have a Committee this Evening, ſo I ſhall hardly ſee you at <hi>Garraways;</hi> but if you pleaſe, let us meet again here to morrow by twelve a Clock.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>I will not fail to meet you at that time.</p>
            </sp>
            <pb n="18" facs="tcp:48951:10"/>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>YOur Servant Sir, I find you are punctual to your time; nor had I been leſs ſo, but that I was ſtopt by one of our Directors in the Street: and by what he told me I per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive you need not trouble your ſelf any further to anſwer my Arguments againſt the expediency of a Rotation; for he ſaith that By-Law was rejected laſt night by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee, and inſtead thereof, they have agreed that eight Directors ſhall fall off every Year, not by way of Rotation, but as it is in the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and by a late Regulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on in the Old <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company; ſo that now ſixteen of the preſent Directors may be continued for Life. And yet I muſt tell you we are very much diſpleaſed even with this By-Law, as it is moderated; for none of us are willing to loſe our places, and ſome of us muſt out, and perhaps it will not be eaſie for us to get in again. And beſides, we are afraid the General Court will confirm this becauſe of thoſe Precedents I have juſt now mentioned; whereas a Rotation being a new Thing, and what People do not well under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand, we were conſident by our Selves, our Friends and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, to have got that rejected by the General Court. For we know when the Directors are unanimous, as they are in that matter, they can govern General Courts as they pleaſe. And moreover, you have few in the Committee that are good Speakers; and thoſe that can talk we ſhall blow them as peeviſh, ſowr, ill-natur'd fellows, State-Reformers, never pleas'd with any thing but what they do themſelves, who made this ſtruggle for a Rotation, not that they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liev'd it for the Intereſt and Safety of the Company, but to get themſelves into our Places. And when Men are once blown, what they ſay (tho never ſo reaſonable and to the purpoſe) is little regarded. We have many friends and others that have meaſures to keep with us upon various Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts, that will concur with our Opinion without Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and believe as we believe: that as we have prevailed to reject a Rotation by the Committee, ſo we do not yet
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:48951:10"/>wholly deſpair of getting this rejected by the General Court, and then we ſhall be fixt for ever. The next Committee for By-Laws (if we ever think fit to have another) ſhall be better modell'd, Men more in our Intereſt; for by that time we ſhall know the humours and inclinations of Men better than we did when we made our Liſt for this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee: had we known you as we do now, the greateſt part of you ſhould not have been in our Liſt, nor conſequently choſen. We have ſome indeed amongſt you that concur with us in every thing we propoſe or oppoſe, and it is ſuch we muſt chuſe hereafter.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>I had ſeveral other things to offer for the expediency of a Rotation; but ſince that Method is rejected by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee, I ſhall ſay little farther upon that Head at this time: yet I am very confident it will not be long before ſuch a Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation be eſtabliſhed. The Thing is now new, many have not heard of it, and others not conſider'd it. But when the Members of the Company ſhall duly weigh the Convenien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies and Safety of it, as ſecuring us againſt the Corruption and ill Practices that the Managers of ſuch Societies have uſually fallen into, by being long continued in their Stations, it will ſoon determine them to the Choice of this Method, rather than that which the Committee hath agreed upon. The falling off of eight yearly, tho not by Rotation, is a good ſtep towards preventing the Miſchiefs that are apt to grow where there is no Change at all; but it is an im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perfect Cure, and will leave us languiſhing. For ſixteen may, and probably moſt of them will be continued for Life without a Rotation; whereas by a thorow Change in three Years all Combinations would be broke, and all undue Means of enriching themſelves diſcovered and prevented: and when they have no ways left to make private Advanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges to themſelves, they will employ their Thoughts for the Intereſt and Profit of the joynt Concern, which are the on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly things aimed at by this Method.</p>
               <p>The deſign of leaving out eight Directors yearly by the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and the Regulation in the Old <hi>Eaſt-India</hi>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:48951:11"/>Company, was the ſame with what we propoſe by a Rota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: and if this will anſwer the End better, it ought not to be rejected for being New or wanting a Precedent. There was no Precedent for thoſe then, no more than for this now; ſo the newneſs of the thing can be no good Reaſon againſt it. That was oppos'd as violently by thoſe Directors then, as this is now by Ours, and they kept it off till the Parliament undertook it: and had they not done ſo, 'tis like it had never been done, nor ever one Director chang'd, except volunta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily or by Death. Tho I muſt obſerve to you that as there is not in the Bank of <hi>England</hi> one tenth part of the opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities of getting Mony by indirect Means as there is in this Company, ſo there is not that occaſion there for a Rotation of their Directors. It ſeems a little ſtrange that abundance of the Members and others ſhould ſee good Reaſon for a Rotation, and yet not one Director ſhould be of that Opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion, but unanimouſly oppoſe it: one would conclude hence that there is ſomething beſides Reaſon governs their Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, for I dare ſay, they are not ſo unanimous in other Matters where their Intereſt is not concerned.</p>
               <p>What you tell me of modelling the next Committee for By-Laws, makes me dread a continuance of the ſame Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors: for ſuch a Set will make all our Committees both for By-Laws and thoſe to audit the Company's Accompts and every thing elſe. And what Good we may expect from Men of their own chuſing, after they perfectly know them, is very eaſie to gueſs: for it is amazing to ſee Committee Men agree exactly with the Directors in every Vote, and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent in none; it looks like an implicit Faith, and that they are guided by other Mens Reaſon rather than their own.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>I think we are now over the matter of a Rotation, and its younger Brother, the leaving out of eight, which we muſt ſubmit to the determination of a General Court. Pray let us conſider another thing that is prepared for a By-Law (which I hear found no oppoſition by any in the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee) And that is, that no Officer or Servant of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany ſhall take directly or indirectly any Fee or Reward
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:48951:11"/>whatſoever for any Service in the Company, but what ſhall be allowed by the Court of Directors. You have herein cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly done well, and what will pleaſe all the Members, and remedy thoſe Evils that are in moſt Companies, and almoſt all Offices in <hi>England.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>The By-Law you ſpeak of concerning the Company's Servants will doubtleſs be agreeable to every one. You ſay we have certainly done well, and I muſt tell you we would have done better if we could: for when the By-Law you laſt mentioned was agreed on, it was moved, that there might be alſo another By-Law to reſtrain the Directors from receiving any Preſents, Gifts or Rewards, beſides their Salaries: and had thoſe Directors that were then preſent ſeconded that Motion, it would have look'd honeſt and gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous; but inſtead of that they put it off with a Joke. And to be plain with you, I think there is more Reaſon for the one than the other, by how much greater Temptations the Directors will have than their Servants: their Servants can only accommodate Men in trifling matters, compar'd to thoſe the Directors may do. And I dare ſay the Directors were more careful and cautious, and made better enquiry be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they choſe their Servants, than we did when we choſe them. I would allow them generous Salaries to reward them for their Care, Trouble and Time; but they ſhould not be allowed to receive any Preſents or Gifts from Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manders of Ships, Factors, or any body elſe concerned with the Company.</p>
               <p n="1">1. And here let me give you the words of a late Author on this Subject we are upon. <q rend="inline">The taking of a Bribe or Gratuity ſhould be puniſhed with as ſevere Penalties as the defrauding the State. Let Men have ſufficient Salaries, and exceed them at their Peril. It is a diſhonour to a Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment that its Officers ſhould live of Benevolence, as it ought to beinfamous to Officers to diſhonour the Publick by being twice paid for the ſame Buſineſs. But to be paid and not to do Buſineſs is rank oppreſſion. Diſpatch is a great and
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:48951:12"/>good Quality in an Officer, where Duty not Gain excites it: but of this many make their private Market and over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus to their Wages. Thus the Salary is for doing, and the Bribe for diſpatching the Buſineſs: as if Buſineſs could be done before it were diſpatched, or what ought to be done ought not to be diſpatched; or they were to be paid a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part, one by the Government, t'other by the Party. Diſpatch is as much the Duty of an Officer as Doing.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. A Preſent or a Gift to any Perſon in a publick Truſt made by a Perſon concerned in thoſe Affairs, or that Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of which he hath the Management, I reckon a plain direct Bribe, and as ſuch will blind their Eyes that receive them. The Sacred Scriptures confirm this Truth, and tell us, <hi>Thou ſhalt take no Gift, for the Gift hlindeth the Wiſe, and perver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teth the words of the Righteous.</hi> Solomon ſaith, <hi>A Gift is as a pretious Stone in the Eyes of him that hath it; whither ſoever it turneth it proſpereth. Awicked Man taketh a Gift out of the bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſom to pervert the ways of Judgment.</hi> And again, <hi>A Man's Gift maketh room for him, and bringeth him before great Men. Many will entreat the favour of the Prince, and every Man is a friend to him that giveth Gifts.</hi> And again further, <hi>A Gift in ſecret pacifieth Anger, and a Reward in the boſom ſtrong Wrath. The King by Judgment ſtabliſheth the Land: But he that recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veth Gifts overthroweth it.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>This would be a pretty ſevere Law indeed to tie us up from taking of Gifts: Who would be a Director on thoſe Terms? If a Commander ſhould ſend me a Chine of Beef, or a few Marrow-Bones, I muſt refuſe them, leſt it be inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preted a Bribe. Every Man that is a Director will expect ſome ſmall Perquiſites beſides his Salary; otherwiſe who would have given five hundred pound to be continued Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee Man in the Old <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company for the ſake of a trifling Allowance every time they gave their attendance? So that ſmall matters ought to be indulged us, ſince 'tis a common Practice, and cannot hurt the Company becauſe other Men pay for it.</p>
            </sp>
            <pb n="23" facs="tcp:48951:12"/>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>Every Man will know on what Terms he muſt hold his Directorſhip; and if he diſlike them, he need not accept of it, but leave it to thoſe that will: ſo there will be no hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip put upon any Man when he knows the Conditions be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore hand. And doubtleſs no body will think him fit to be a Director that accepts of it, and is not contented with his bare Salary, and the honour of the Place. But it is odd to talk of indulging ſmall Perquiſites, little Gifts, and Bribes; as if the taking a ſmall Bribe were not a Crime: the taking of the leaſt is doubtleſs ſo, and as ſuch ought not to be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed. We may as well permit Men to rob as far as five or ten ſhillings, but no higher, and ſay the ſmallneſs of the Sum renders it lawful: whereas all that can be ſaid for it is, that the inconſiderableneſs of the Robbery doth extenuate, but not legitimate the Fact. Beſides, it may be juſtly feared, that thoſe who allow themſelves a liberty to ſteal five or ten ſhillings, will make no Conſcience of taking a larger Sum when they have an opportunity to do it. If we ſhould allow them to accept of ſmall things, pray how ſhall we ſet them exact Bounds beyond which they are not to paſs? I am afraid ſuch a Liberty would find no bounds, and can no more be reſtrained, than Water that breaks down the Banks, which will overflow as well where we would not, as where we are willing it ſhould.</p>
               <p>We have heard of Managers in another Company, who have not contented themſelves with Marrow-Bones, China-Ware, Tea, and other little Rarities; but have gone as high as a Bale of Muzlin of a great Value: and in the Pocket-Book of the late Captain of the — there was found written, <hi>Given to ſuch a Committee Man three hundred and fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty pound to hold one ſixteenth of my Ship, to another two hundred and fifty pound to hold ſuch a Part, and to a third, one hundred and fifty pound to hold one two and thirtieth part.</hi> Thus you ſee, where Men have liberty, they will not know where to ſtop. Weak People may fancy that the Company loſt nothing by what the Captain gave the Committee Men, becauſe it went
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:48951:13"/>immediately out of his pocket, and not out of the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny's: but doubtleſs the Captain did not part with his Mony for Air; he laid it out to good Advantage, and that at the long run the Company paid for, and not the Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tee Men who received it.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>But you have prepared another By-Law; That once a Year a Committee of five, whereof three to make a <hi>Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum,</hi> ſhall be choſen by the General Court to audit the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts, and inſpect the Proceedings of the Company; and if they find any thing amiſs, to report it to the next Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Court. This is a By-Law we do extreamly diſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove; it looks like the effect of Jealouſie, and will have ill conſequences, by betraying the Secrets of the Company to all the World: and ſome things may be of that nature, that the diſcloſing of them might be very prejudicial to the Affairs of the Company. Beſides, it looks very unkind, while we have done no unjuſtifiable Action, but are labou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring day and night for your Service, that you ſhould make this diſtruſtful Law, which it had been time enough to have done when you had known us do ſomething amiſs: and moreover, we are under an Oath which ties us to do you Juſtice, and is alone a ſufficient Security.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>It ſeems ſtrange to me, and doubtleſs will do ſo to others, that the Directors do ſo eaſily conſent to all By-Laws wherein their Directorſhips or private Advantages are not concerned, and at the ſame time ſhould ſo violently op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe all By-Laws that would hinder them from doing us wrong, and diſcover them when they do ſo. If they in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to do nothing amiſs, why are they afraid of Laws that can hurt none but evil Doers? Men that are honeſt, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve to continue ſo, need neither fear nor be concerned, what ſevere Laws ſoever are made to puniſh thoſe that are otherwiſe. If a Law was preparing to inflict even Capital Puniſhment on ſuch as ſhould take a Bribe, why ſhould I op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe it except I intended to take one my ſelf? For however a Law of this Nature may be, it can puniſh none but wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:48951:13"/>Tranſgreſſours of it, and ſuch will not deſerve pity, for none can be ſurpriz'd and ſo tranſgreſs ignorantly or inad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertently; and it is ſuch only that merit Compaſſion, and Relaxation of a ſevere Law.</p>
               <p>What need you fear an Inſpection of your Accompts and Proceedings, if they be juſt and fair? for then it will be for your Advantage to have the World know they are ſo, whereas without ſuch an Inſpection you may lie under ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>picion and an ill Character, when you deſerve it not; ſo that methinks for your own Reputation, even you your ſelves ſhould deſire ſuch a By-Law. And I hope it cannot be call'd Jealouſie in us to believe you are Men like your neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours. We have heard of ill things frequently done by Perſons in other publick Truſts, and why then is it ſo un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pardonable in us, to think that it is poſſible, at leaſt for ſome of you to do ſo too, when you are under the ſame Temptations? We do this by way of Precaution and for Prevention, and not becauſe we ſuſpect or know you to be ill Men already. To let this By-Law alone till you have tranſgreſſed, would be both imprudent in us, and unſafe for you: for Laws and the Fear of Detection and Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment keep ſome Men in the right way, whom Opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity and Temptation would otherwiſe lead aſide. As to the Oath you mentioned; I confeſs an Oath is ſo ſacred a Thing, that there would need no ſtronger Tye upon a truly conſcientious Man; but taking Men in general as they are, there needs ſome additional Security, and it is the declared Opinion of one of our eminenteſt Directors, <hi>That one Bond is worth fifty Oaths.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>But then you ſay, this Committee will betray the Secrets of the Company, and ill Conſequences will attend it. I hope both the Directors and the General Court will endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to chuſe ſuch Men for that Committee as have a fair Reputation for Honeſty and Diſcretion, and whoſe Intereſt it will be to keep all neceſſary Secrets of the Company. If twenty four Directors can keep a Secret, certainly five
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:48951:14"/>Committee-Men can do ſo too, when they have all the ſame honeſt Obligations upon them to do it as the Directors. They will be Members of the Company, take the uſual Oaths, and be tyed by their Intereſts in the Stock, equally with the Directors: And if any thing of Moment ſhall be thought fit to be entruſted with a few Directors, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealed from the reſt, the ſame Reaſons that made thoſe reſt ſatisfied without the knowledg of it, will doubtleſs prevail with the Committee to be ſo too. And as to ſecret Services at home, I would not have them concealed; for if we cannot thrive and ſupport our Selves without Bribery and Corruption here, it is more eligible to have the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany ſuffer any Inconveniences, than be ſupported by ſuch unwarrantable m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>n, as have ſo long preſerv'd the Old Company from a diſolution.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>There is I hear another ill-natur'd By-Law prepared, which is, that after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> 1699, no Director ſhall be concerned as an Owner in any Ships they hire for the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, ſo that if I have a Part of a Ship, ſhe cannot ſerve the Company becauſe I am a Part-Owner: which is a cruel hardſhip upon the Directors, and may occaſion the want of proper Ships to ſerve the Company.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>We were choſen to prepare ſuch By-Laws as we judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for the Safety and Advantage of the Company, ſo that our Buſineſs is to purſue thoſe Ends, and not to conſult the Profit and Conveniences of any particular Directors or Members of it. Their Intereſt is not our Care to provide for, where it may interfere with that of the Society, as doubtleſs ſuch a Liberty would do: for if Directors might hire their own Ships, or ſuch as they are Part-Owners of, adjuſt their Damages, Demurrages, Averages, and allow the Commanders Licences to trade, we may expect they will be more favourable to their own Intereſt than that of the Company, by how much the one is nearer to them than the other. And when Directors may freight their own Ships, any Tool they have, will be adjudged fit for our Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice:
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:48951:14"/>whereas when they are not concern'd themſelves, and ſo not byaſs'd by their Intereſt, they will not fail to be curious and nice in their Choice, and we ſhall be ſure to have the beſt and propereſt Ships the Kingdom affords, and upon the beſt Terms.</p>
               <p>To let the Directors be both Buyers and Sellers of their own Commodities, (and letting and hiring their own Ships is the ſame thing) would be an unaccountable folly in us; and I hope the loſs and inconveniences the Old Company have ſuffered by that Liberty, will be a ſufficient warning to us to avoid the ſame Errour.</p>
               <p>At preſent there are not many of our Directors con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd in ſuch Shipping as is proper for the <hi>India</hi> Trade; therefore this By-Law can be only an Inconvenience to a few; and why we ſhould, for the Advantage of five or ſix Directors, neglect the making of a Law that will for ever ſecure the Company from many miſchiefs, which may at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend us by wanting ſuch a Law, is what I cannot underſtand; beſides, it will be leſs prejudicial to the Directors, and eaſier obtain'd, to make ſuch a By-Law now, while they are little concern'd in Shipping, than hereafter; when by ſuch a Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty their Concern in it is become much greater. And, without pretending to a Spirit of Prophecy, I will affirm, that before we are ſix Months older, thoſe Directors who are not concern'd in the Shipping you ſhall freight for this Seaſon, will not have ſuch an averſion to this By-Law as they now ſeem to have.</p>
               <p>If any Director have a ſmall Part of a Ship that is fit for the <hi>India</hi> Trade, which by this Law cannot ſerve the Company till that Director hath ſold his Part, the reſt of the Owners will readily buy it, almoſt on his own Terms, to make her free for the Company's Service, ſo that in that Caſe which is thought the hardeſt, the Director can ſuffer no Loſs, but will be rather a Gainer: But if his Part be very large, every one may gueſs how that will byaſs him to the Company's Prejudice.</p>
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:48951:15"/>
               <p>It may be ſaid, thoſe Directors that are not concern'd in Shipping may hire Ships, adjuſt Damages, Demurrages, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But every body knows how apt thoſe that ſit at the ſame Board are to favour one another, ſo that ſuch a Method will but deceive us, and can be no Security to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany; beſides, thoſe Directors that have not been con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd in Shipping, will want Skill and Experience to ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage thoſe Affairs, and cannot be thought ſo proper to compoſe a Committee of Shipping, as others that have been long acquainted with the nature of it.</p>
               <p>And while I am ſpeaking of Committees, let me obſerve to you, that a By-Law for a Change or Rotation amongſt the ſeveral Committees as well as amongſt the Directors at the Annual Election, would in my Opinion be of great Advantage and Security to the Company, both for pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venting Corruption, and giving each Director an oppor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunity to be acquainted with all the Affairs of the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny; whereas by continuing the ſame Committees, they will be almoſt Strangers to all other Buſineſs but that under their particular management.</p>
               <p>We have liberty by our Charter to make what By-Laws we pleaſe for our Security and good Government; and ſince we have ſeen thoſe Rocks and Sands on which the Old Company have ſplit, we ſhall be extreamly wanting to our ſelves and our Poſterity, if we do not provide ſufficiently againſt them, but ſuffer our ſelves to be bubled out of our Safety and Senſes, by Sophiſtry and falſe Reaſoning.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>D.</speaker>
               <p>You ſeem mighty warm for your By-Laws, as if they were ſo great a Security to the Company againſt the ill Practices of the Directors: whereas if we were ill Men, it would require no great thought or cunning to elude the force of moſt of them, and more particularly your By-Law about Shipping and that againſt receiving Gifts or Bribes, as you call them: therefore when all is done you muſt truſt to our honeſty.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C.</speaker>
               <p>I am ſenlible there is a great deal of Truth in what
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:48951:15"/>you now ſay; yet it is no good Argument againſt having By-Laws, becauſe ill Men may elude them; they will how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever be ſome Awe and Reſtraint upon them (if ever we ſhould have ſuch Directors) leſt they ſhould be diſcover'd. But if By-Laws cannot reſtrain them, or ſecure us; nor Mens Integrity be intirely depended upon, by reaſon of the general Corruption of Mankind, then, as I ſaid before, (with which I will conclude) The beſt and only good Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity we can have againſt the evil Practices of bad Men, and ſubjecting our beſt Men to Temptations, will be a fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent change of Hands, by a thorow Rotation of the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors in the ſpace of three Years. For if the Director<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip be but of a ſhort continuance, and none enjoy it above three Years ſucceſſively, they cannot have time to form and accompliſh private Deſigns before they be remo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved; for thoſe that ſucceed them will diſcover their In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trigues, and break all their Meaſures. And (which may be of no ſmall Advantage and Security to us) Men will be at a loſs where to place their Gifts, when the Power and op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity of recompencing them, is by this means become ſo precarious and uncertain.</p>
            </sp>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="notice">
            <head>Advertiſement.</head>
            <p>THis Dialogue was prepared ſeveral Months ago, but the Publication of it was defer'd till the By-Laws to be propoſed to the General Court were finiſh'd; by which means ſome Paſſages in it may have elapſed their time.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:48951:16"/>
            <head>BOOKS ſold by <hi>Andrew Bell</hi> in <hi>Cornhil.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>DIſcourſes concerning Government, by <hi>Algernon Sidney,</hi> Son to <hi>Robert</hi> Earl of <hi>Leiceſter,</hi> and Ambaſſador from the Commonwealth of <hi>England</hi> to <hi>Charles Guſtavus</hi> King of <hi>Sweden. Publiſhed from an Original Manuſcript of the Author.</hi> Price 16 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A complete Collection of the Hiſtorical, Political, and Miſcellaneous Works of <hi>John Milton,</hi> both Engliſh and Latin. With ſome Papers never before publiſh'd. In 3 Vol. To which is preſix'd, The Life of the Author, containing, beſides the Hiſtory of his Works, ſeveral extraordinary Characters of Men and Books, Sects, Parties, and Opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons. Price 40 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The General Hiſtory of <hi>England</hi> both Eccleſiaſtical and Civil, from the earlieſt Accounts of Time to the Reign of his preſent Majeſty King <hi>William</hi> III. Taken from the moſt antient Records, Manuſcripts and Hiſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rians. Containing the Lives of the Kings, and Memorials of the moſt Eminent Perſons both in Church and state. With the Foundations of the Noted Monaſteries, and both the Univerſities. Vol. I. By <hi>James Tyriel</hi> Eſq; Fol. Price 1 <hi>l.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Inquiry concerning Virtue, in two Diſcourſes: the firſt of Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue, and the belief of a Deity; the ſecond, of the Obligations to Virtue. Price in Calf 2 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Eſſe concerning the Power of the Mariſtrate, and the Rights of Mankind in Matters of Religion. With ſome Reilons in particular for the Diſſenter not being oblig'd to take the Sacramental Teſt but in their own Churches, and for a General Naturalization. Together with a Poſtſcript in anſwer to the Letter to a Convocation-man. Price in Calf 2 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Detection of the Court and State of <hi>England</hi> during the 4 laſt Reigns and the <hi>Interregnum;</hi> conſiſting of private Memoirs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> With Obſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Betlections; and an <hi>Appendix</hi> diſcovering the preſent State of the Nation. Wherein are many <hi>Secrets</hi> never before made publick; as alſo a more importial Account of the Civil Wars in <hi>England</hi> than has yet been gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven. by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Eſq; The 3d Edition very much corrected, with an Alphabetical Table. Price 7 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Account of the firſt Voyages and Diſcoveries made by the <hi>Spaniards</hi> in <hi>America;</hi> containing the moſt exact Relation hitherto publiſh'd, of their unparallel'd Cruelties on the <hi>Indians,</hi> in the deſtruction of above 40 Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions of People. Together with the Propoſitions offered to the King of <hi>Spain</hi> to prevent the further Ruin of the <hi>Weſt-Indies.</hi> By <hi>Don Bartholomew de las Caſas,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Chiapa,</hi> who was an Eye witneſs of their Cruel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties. Illuſtrated with Cuts. To which is added, <hi>The Art of Travelling,</hi> ſhew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing. how a Man may diſpoſe his Travels to the beſt advantage. Price in Calf 4 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Art of Memory: A Treatiſe uſeful for all, eſpecially ſuch as are to ſpeak in publick. By <hi>Marius D' Aſſigny</hi> B. D. Price 1 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:48951:16"/>
            <head>A Catalogue of Books written againſt a ſtanding Army and ſold by <hi>A. Baldwin.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>AN Argument ſhewing, that a Standing Army is inconſiſtent with a Free Government, and abſolutely deſtructive to the Conſtitution of the Engliſh Monarchy. In 2 Parts. Price 1 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Letter from the Author of the Argument againſt a Standing Army, to the Author of the Ballancing Letter. Price 3 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Some Queries for the better underſtanding K. <hi>James</hi>'s Liſt of 18000 Iriſh Heroes publiſhed at the <hi>Savoy,</hi> in anſwer to what had bin, and what ſhould be writ againſt a Standing Army. Price 1 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Diſcourſe concerning Government, with relation to Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litia's. Price 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Militia Reform'd, or an eaſy Scheme of furniſhing <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> with a conſtant Land Force, capable to prevent or to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>due any Foreign Power, and to maintain perpetual Quiet at home, without endangering the Publick Liberty. The <hi>2d</hi> Edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Price 1 <hi>s.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A ſhort Hiſtory of Standing Armies in <hi>England.</hi> The <hi>3d</hi> Edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Price 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Confutation of a late Pamphlet intituled, A Letter ballancing the Neceſſity of keeping up a Land Force in times of Peace, with the Dangers that may follow on it. Part I. The <hi>2d</hi> Edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Price 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Letter to a Member of Parliament concerning Guards and Gariſons. Price 2 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A <hi>2d</hi> Letter concerning the four Regiments commonly called Mareeners. Price 3 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Seaman's Opinion of a Standing Army, in oppoſition to a Fleet at Sea as the beſt ſecurity of the Kingdom. In a Letter to a Merchant, written by a Sailor. The <hi>3d</hi> Edition. Price 6 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Some further Conſiderations concerning a Standing Army Price. 3 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The State of the Caſe, or the Caſe of the State. Price 1 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
